<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <title>Triggers and Action Execution in Assessment</title>

  <chapter>
    <title>Design</title>

    <section>
      <title>Data Model</title>

      <para>It was necessary to add several tables to support the trigger and
      action execution.<screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/asm_dm.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para><figure>
          <screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/as_inter_item_checks.JPG" />
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot>
        </figure><screenshot>
          <screeninfo></screeninfo>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/as_actions.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot><screenshot>
          <screeninfo></screeninfo>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/as_action_map.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot><screenshot>
          <screeninfo></screeninfo>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/as_action_params.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot><screenshot>
          <screeninfo></screeninfo>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/as_param_map.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot><screenshot>
          <screeninfo></screeninfo>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/as_actions_log.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>User Manual</title>

    <para>Here are some statements to create triggers to branch between
    sections or execute actions:</para>

    <section>
      <title>Manage Permissions</title>

      <para>To create an assessment is necessary to have create permissions
      over the assessment instance. This permission can be inherit or can be
      granted by a site wide administrator. This permissions can be managed by
      the site wide administrator following the Permissions link in the
      assessment admin page.</para>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/create_permissions.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>

      <para>To create triggers is necessary to have admin permissions over an
      assessment. The admin permission is inherit to the user that creates an
      assessment and also can be granted by the assessment administrator. This
      permissions can be managed folloging the Permission link that appears in
      the list of assessments.</para>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/asm_admin_permissions.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>

      <para>Both links will lead the user to a page where the necessary
      permissions can be set.</para>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/manage_permissions.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>

      <para>Also the user can search for another user to manage his
      permissions:</para>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/search_user.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>

      <para>After clicking OK, the user will appear in the list an the
      permissions can be set properly.</para>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/user_permissions.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Actions Administration</title>

      <para>To be able to administrate actions the user must have site wide
      admin privileges. To admin actions the user must follow the link "Action
      Administration" in the assessment admin page.</para>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/admin_actions.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Register User: create a new user account in the system.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Event Registration: register the user to an event.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Add to Community: register the user to dotlrn and also to a
          dotlrn class/community.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <para>Actions can be also created, following the link "Add new
      action":</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/add_action.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>The action is formed mainlly by four things:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Name: the desire name that gives an idea of what the action
          do.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Description: short explanation of what the action do, and how
          its done.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Tcl code: the code that its executed to performe the
          action.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Parameter: this are the variables needed in the tcl code, that
          depends of the user.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/create_action.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>

      <para>After the action is created, a link to add the parameters is
      shown.</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/add_params.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>When the link is followed, then a form to create the
      parameter is shown, there are two types of parameters:</para>

      <para><orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Name: this will take the value from a response given by the
            user to an item of the assessment.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Query: for this type of parameter, the field query is used,
            and the parameter will take the value or values that the query
            returns.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/create_param.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>To delete an action the link "delete" in the action administration
      page must be followed:</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/delete_action.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>Before deleting an action, a confirm message will be
      displayed, the action will not be deleted if there is some reference to
      this action (i.e. a trigger that wil execute this action).<screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/action_del_confirm.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Trigger Definition</title>

      <para>After the assessment is created, the triggers can be defined for
      questions with multiple choice responses.</para>

      <para>There are two type of triggers:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Branch: This trigger will make that the secuence of sections
          in the assessment change, depending on the answer that a user gives
          to the question related to the trigger when the assessment is being
          responded.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Action: This trigger will execute the action related, also
          depending on the answer that the user gives to the question related
          to the trigger, when the assessment is being responded.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The link to create a trigger appears in the action bar of the
      items with multiple choice responses of the assessment.</para>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/add_trigger.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Branch Triggers</title>

      <para>To define a Branch Trigger, the field "Type" in the form must be
      checked as branch. Is necessary that at least one section is created
      after the one that is being evaluated.</para>

      <para>The condition field shows the question and its possible answers,
      this means that if a user that respond the assessment choose that
      response the trigger will be activated, and the section secuence will
      change.</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/branch_trigger.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>After the trigger is defined as branch, the section that will be
      displayed next must be chosen:</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/select_section.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Action Triggers</title>

      <para>To define an Action Trigger, the field "Type" in the form must be
      checked as "Action".</para>

      <para>The condition field shows the question and its possible anwers, it
      means that when the user is responding the assessment, if this answer is
      given for this question, the action will be executed.</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/action_trigger.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>After the trigger is created, the action related must be chosen,
      also the time when the action will be executed, and the message shown to
      the user when the action is executed.</para>

      <para>The actions can be executed in three different times:</para>

      <para><orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Immediately: it means that the action will be executed after
            the user finish to respond the current section.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>At the end of this Assessment: it means that the action will
            be executed when the user finish to respond all the sections of
            the assessment.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Manually:this means that the action will be executed by an
            administrator (i.e. in case that the request needs
            approval).</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/select_action.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>After select the action related to the trigger, the parameters for
      the action must be set, the select boxes display the options depending
      on the type of the parameter.</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Query: display the values returned by the query defined for
          the parameter.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Name: the options displayed depends on the time of
          execution:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Immediately: display all the questions defined in previuos
              sections.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>At the end of the assessment and Manually: display all the
              questions defined in the assessment.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/set_params.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Trigger Administration</title>

      <para>The trigger administration page can be reached from two different
      links, the link "Administer Triggers" in the action bar of each section,
      or from the link that show the number of triggers related to an
      item.</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/checks_admin.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>If the trigger administration page is reached from thi link of the
      section, all the triggers related to the items of the section will be
      display, this allowst to manage the order of the execution of the
      actions when they are executed immediately or at the end or the
      assessment. When the arrorws that appear beside each trigger is clicked,
      then the order of execution will change.</para>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/section_triggers.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>

      <para>If the trigger administration page is reached through the link
      that show the number of triggers of each item, then the row will not be
      shown. Through this interface, the trigger can be edited, deleted or can
      be managed its notifications.</para>

      <para>When a trigger is deleted, a confirm message will be display
      showing all the information related to it.<screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/delete_triggers.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>The link "Notify User" leads to a page a user can request
      notifications when this trigger is executed. It also allowst to search
      and register another users to the notifications.</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/notifications.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Request Administration</title>

      <para>The request Administration page can be reached following the link
      in the action bar for a site wide administrator or following the link
      show in the list of assessments that belong to a user.</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/request_admin.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>The Request Administration interface shows all the requests
      (action triggers executions) that has been approved, approved with
      errors and the ones that are waiting to be executed (i.e. Manually
      executed triggers).</para>

      <para>This interface will display those requests related to the
      assessments that the user owns, if the user is site wide administrator,
      all the requests related to all the assessments will be display.</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/show_requests.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>

      <para>An administrator can select requests that want to approve and
      click in the button "Approve", and also can send mail to several users
      that requested the action. Through this interface the notifications can
      also be managed.</para>

      <para><screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/request_actions.JPG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot></para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Registration Assessment</title>

    <para>To be able to select an assessment that will be related to the
    registration process is necessary that the user has site wide admin
    privileges, because the interface can only be reached through the Main
    Site Administration Page. This link only will appear if the Assessment
    Package is installed and mounted.</para>

    <para><screenshot>
        <screeninfo></screeninfo>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/register_asm.JPG" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>If the Assessment Package is installed and mounted, the
    link can be follow and will lead to a page that shows all the assessment
    that can be responded for anonymous users created in all of the different
    instances of the assessment package that could exist. If the option "None"
    is selected, it means that the registration process will be the same as
    always has been, if any other option is selected, the assessment will be
    displayed when a user creates a new account.</para>

    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/none_asm.JPG" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/select_asm.JPG" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Authors</title>

    <para>Viaro Networks (www.viaro.net)</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Rocael Hernandez -- roc@viaro.net</para>

        <para>Design</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Vivian Aguilar -- vivian@viaro.net</para>

        <para>Desing and Development</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Anny Flores -- annyflores@viaro.net</para>

        <para>Development and Documentation</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </chapter>
</book>
